After you calculate returns from a trading signal,
当你根据交易信号计算出收益后
you may suspect the presence of outliers when you
你在检查信号收益的分布图时
examine the distribution of your signal returns.
可能会怀疑存在离群值
Let me explain what I mean by that.
我来解释下
Imagine that we've written some code to generate a trading signal and we've
假设我们写了段交易信号的代码
calculated our monthly returns from a couple years of trading based on this signal,
并且根据此信号计算出几年间的每月收益
what would we expect the distribution of returns to look like?
我们预期收益是什么样的分布图？
Let's figure out what we would expect to see in a few limiting scenarios.
我们看看在几种情形下的预期结果
What if we picked our buy and sell times at random?
如果随机选择买卖时间会怎样？
In that case, we wouldn't expect to make any money because we'll be
我们预计不会获得任何收益
equally likely to buy or sell when the market is going up or down.
因为当市场上下波动时 我们的买入或卖出概率是一样的
We'd expect our returns to have a normal distribution with mean zero,
我们预计收益将是正态分布 均值为零
but what if we designed a trading strategy that performed well?
如果我们设计出业绩不错的交易策略呢？
Ideally, if a trading signal looks like it will perform well,
理想情况下 如果交易信号看起来业绩不错
the distribution of its returns should look like
收益分布图应该看起来像
a slightly positively skewed normal distribution.
稍微正偏斜的正态分布
For the signal to make money,
交易信号要获利
returns should be positive and non-zero on average.
收益应该为正 并且平均值不为零
So, the distributions mean should be above zero.
所以分布均值应该大于零
However, sometimes the return distribution can
但是 有时候收益分布图
look a little too good or just plain weird.
看起来过于好或者很奇怪
This should arouse your skepticism.
这时候你就要注意了
Extremely skewed shapes or bumps at either tail of the histogram spell trouble.
过于偏斜的形状或在直方图的两端隆起表明有问题
One tool you can use to compare your distribution of returns to
你可以用 QQ 图来比较你的收益分布与
another distribution like the normal distribution is the QQ plot.
其他分布 如正态分布
A QQ plot is a plot of the quantiles of
QQ 图是指第一个数据集的分位数
the first data set against the quantiles of the second data set.
与第二个数据集的分位数进行比较的图形
What are quantiles?
什么是分位数
Well, if we split a data set into four equally sized groups,
如果我们将数据集均匀地拆分成四等分
the dividing lines are at the 25th, 50th,
拆分线分别是第 25 百分位 第 50 百分位和第 75 百分位
and 75th percentiles, these are usually called quartiles.
这些拆分线通常称为分位数
The 50th percentile is the median,
第 50 百分位是中值
the value below which 50% the data fall.
有 50% 的值小于它
Quartiles divide the data set into four groups,
四分位将数据集拆分为四部分
but with quantiles, the dataset can be divided into any number of equally-sized groups.
但是分位数可以将数据集拆分成任意数量的等份
For example, you could have ten quantiles,
例如 可以有十个分位数
these are usually called deciles.
通常称为十分位数
The word quantile is usually used to denote the cut points,
分位数通常表示划分点
but it's sometimes used to refer to the groups themselves.
但有时候表示小组本身
Let's get back to the goal of comparing
我们再回到
your distribution of returns to the normal distribution.
将收益分布图与正态分布图相比上
If you wanted to use QQ plots,
如果你想使用 QQ 图
you would first first the set of quantiles you want to use,
首先需要设置分位数
then you would plot the nth quantile of your distribution against the nth quantile of
然后绘制第 n 分位数 并与正态分布的第 n 分位数进行比较
the normal distribution and continue for all the values of
然后继续绘制所有 n 个分位数
n. If you're comparing your distribution to the normal distribution,
将分布图与正态分布图比较后
and your distribution is approximately normal,
如果你的分布图接近正态分布图
points in the QQ plot should fall along a straight line.
QQ 图中的点应该大致呈直线
If the distribution has fatter tails than the normal distribution,
如果分布图的尾部比正态分布图的更肥
the QQ plot will reveal deviations from a straight line at the extremities of the graph.
QQ 图的末端将偏离直线
Distributions with skew will also have QQ plots that curve away from a straight line.
偏斜分布图的 QQ 图也会偏离直线
A good quant should try to understand the root cause of outliers and returns.
优秀的量化分析师应该去分析收益离群值的根本缘由
The first step in dealing with a situation like this is to
处理这种情形的第一步是了解
find out where and when the outlying data points occurred,
在何处以及何时出现了离群值
for which stock or stocks and for which dates.
对应哪些股票以及在哪些日期
The next step is to ask why.
下一步是弄明白原因
Depending upon the nature of the extreme data,
离群值的来源可能明显 也可能不太明显
the source might be obvious or less so.
取决于极端数据的特性
Was it a data error?
是数据错误吗？
Was an illegitimate movement due to a real event?
是因为真实事件导致的不合理变化吗？
If an extreme datum looks like it could be real,
如果极端数据看起来像真实情况
you can check the news for the stock on that day.
你可以查询当天的股票新闻
Was there an announcement?
有什么通告吗？
You'll want to think of every possibility you can to
你需要考虑各种可能性
explain why this might not be a market data vendor problem.
确保不是市场数据供应商问题导致的
A good strategy is to crosscheck with another market data source.
好的策略是求证其他市场数据来源